all right here we are it's a new day
we're still working on Harbor testing
and I want to report on what we did and
what we're going to do in the live
stream um this will be the only video
that's posted to YouTube regarding
Harbor for today uh unless I find
something major so uh I'm only going to
do one summary video I mean one kind of
here's what we're doing today and here's
what we discovered from yesterday and
I'll do a video like that every day so
so tomorrow if you want to see the
summary video what I did today what
actually ended up being a reality just
keep watching on YouTube and you can go
watch that video If you um want to
participate and want to watch me go
through the pain and suffering you know
live then come join us on Twitch all
right so yesterday yesterday Beyond
getting mini Cube installed um we also
got uh harbored to install into mini
Cube uh using postgress uh version
16.4 and we did that by fixing the bug
in the values. yaml
file which results from the you know the
regular command uh show whatever Helm
show whatever to get the yam so there's
a bug in the in the val. yo file that
that
pegs uh the vietnami harbor chart to
version 13 of postest is going to be end
of life next year next November so we
wanted to use version 16 and uh we spent
a good amount of time way more than than
I would care to have ever done finding
any reference to which was the standard
version of postgress on in Harbor on the
Harbor documentation and there is none
there is officially no documentation
stating what the recommended postrest
version is for Harbor
2.11 period if you know of any and you
found a reference to it please put it in
the comments below or come in my chat
and let me know because after all of us
spent a lot of time trying to answer
that one simple question what version of
postcards can I use we could not do it
we know that anything past 2.9 according
to the
documentation has to be at least version
12 of postgress and now we're talking
about the version of postgress not the
chart it's really important by the way
uh that you distinguish those two things
um and so that leaves us with a question
can we even use
16.4 uh by reviewing the the the
resulting template file from the helm
template command we were able to see
that there are multiple metadata tags
that refer to postgress version
16.4 uh did I get that
right yeah and 16.4 is more or less the
latest stable
version and it appears uh we went
through looking through the chart and
the chart has hard Cod data reference to
the chart. yel file in the uh bitnami
GitHub repo has 13 Point whatever
hardcoded into the chart. yaml file it's
also hard-coded into the into the into
the values file at with a very outdated
comment saying that this was added to
Peg this to 13 because version 2.4 of
Harbor doesn't support version 14 of
postgress which is ancient history at
this point so based on that we were we
were of the opinion that we could
attempt to change that value in the
values. yl file and that was the only
thing I did so there were other
references to
16.4 inside of the uh inside of the
values file which made me think that
okay this this might work with 16.4 so I
I changed the postgress dosq what is it
uh postgress
do uh image. tag in the values file was
changed to the latest tag for 16.4 that
was referenced and uh I was able to find
that uh exact tag by looking at the
bitnami
postgress uh chart and that is the same
one from that chart all of this would
seem to indicate that the bitnami charts
are built uh by on based on sub charts
on the postc sub charts on the Redd sub
charts and that they are being included
and that they're being used and and that
some parts of the chart the resulting
manifest that comes out of the AML that
comes out of it some parts of that
are uh updated to 16.4 whereas the but
but the but the critical piece that
actually gets the image is still stuck
on 13 unless you overwrite that I happen
to think it's a bug um and I'm trying to
validate that so so today the plan is to
test our postgress uh that's been
installed to test our Harbor that we've
installed in mini cube in my in my test
deployment here on
NVM uh it's very possible that something
about mini Cube running in a VM is not
going to allow Harbor to work um so
we'll be finding that question out if
that doesn't work um I'll probably be
bumping up the time that I the date that
I buy uh a new server Tower and my other
one got fried in the move and so you
know it was refurbished so whatever but
I if that we if this mini Cube test
appointment doesn't work in my home lab
uh stay tuned on Friday for that if you
want to if you want to come in on home
lab Fridays uh Friday afternoon I is
just talking about my own home lab and
sharing notes with everybody so uh
that's the plan if it if if this if it
doesn't work in mini Cube uh for some
reason and we can't validate it then so
what does it mean what does Works mean
right um and that that launched me into
kind of a you know verose uh discussion
about testing particularly at the
Enterprise and in operations what does
it mean to write a test and why do you
need tests right well the you guys know
this but there's test driven development
but the many of the concepts of test
driven development uh despite the debate
around it can be applied to Enterprise
systems development and architecture and
that includes how do I check that this
whole thing works and if you fall in one
of the more traditional like we built
you know uh user user stories or use
cases to Define what's going to happen
in the system if you have have those
things because you developed the system
from scratch then you may already have
you know the steps of validation and a
procedure to go to um however most
people don't have that right and and um
unfortunately Harbor doesn't have any I
it's it's actually one of the biggest
failures of the industry in my opinion
um you barely get documentation about
what the system does this is why you
should learn how to read the source code
of any system you're maintaining because
that's where the truth is and um then
you can go to the next stage which is
how is this thing going to work in our
environment and um if you're an
architect or you're in the operations
space you have already kind of had to
start thinking about these things even
though the applications developers may
not have given you much one of the
biggest talking points in all of
kubernetes and and Cloud native um you
know thinking is uh observability
because all of these crazy you know
microservices are out there how do you
know if they're even working the way
they're supposed
to there's really no answer there
everything's different there's no
standard and every system is different
so there has to be a difference it can't
be automated and so you know and then
how do you know the system so this is
actually this systems this integration
testing the system testing making sure
the thing actually works Works um is
really key it's key for lots of reasons
it's key for monitoring so you can tell
you know in real time is the system
working as designed right I mean that's
the main thing and then there's also
another one our whole system just got we
just got lightning strike in our in our
and our thing and we have to recover our
entire system Disaster Recovery Dr can
you do it how when's the last time you
actually tested your Disaster Recovery
scenario I guarantee you if you work for
the government in certain areas you've
tested it recently there are and
different Enterprises this is one thing
this is one of those things where
Silicon Valley just totally Fells on its
face you know they're all about making
new cool stuff and everything and they
don't care about sustainable disaster
recovery and backup and something like
that I mean that's a large sweeping
statement obviously there's probably
groups that do but this is the thing
that gets swept under the rug all the
time and then this is where I get to be
you know angry man shakes his fist at
you do you have your Disaster Recovery
test when's the last time you tested it
right and there's also security testing
which we're not going to do that's not
what we're doing why am I even talking
about systems integration to Disaster
Recovery I just want to see if I can get
Harbor install the mini cube right the
reason I'm talking about it is because I
can actually accomplish two things at
the same time right
now I can write the steps to validate
that this system is working right in
very specific detail I can write them
actually type them out not put them in
some sort of automated test framework
not spend you know I don't know two days
bike shedding which test framework to
use I can just write down what I need to
do and I can give I can follow the the
plan the
procedure um and so we're going to do
that we're going to do that why are we
going to do that today and it's going to
be very boring but this is going to give
me a written form of validation that the
system is working as designed and it's
going to take the form of the user does
this and this and this or the system
administrator does this and they see
this right and those of course a lot of
those test cases can be put into some
form of of automated test driven
development later you can put them into
your you know your get of actions and
all that stuff but that you have to
start somewhere so you start by writing
the procedure you know writing the
pseudo code of the procedure the user
goes to here click on this look at that
see if that's there let's try to add a
new user let's try to delete a user or a
registry let's uh let's add a project
you know and and this it's it's easy to
get bogged down in the details of this
but you actually have to have this if
you don't have this you never know that
your system is up so after you undergo
an upgrade how are you going to go
regression
test what you have well one of the ways
is you run through your Disaster
Recovery validation and you make sure
that this those procedures and all those
steps you can't just one person's like
oh I checked it and it worked it's all
working is another person's like it's
not working right so I can't tell you
how many times I can't tell you how many
times I have found like critical systems
failures by following a procedure for
this kind of thing and maybe that's why
I get the big books I don't get the big
buck I'm just it also makes me
insufferable to work with because I I
don't like systems that aren't tested
and there's a bunch of cowboys that'll
push something out why is it taking you
so long because I'm writing test cases
and I'm validating that it works we
should have had it done two days
ago stormmy Daniels
yay stormmy welcome welcome to the
stream now you're in my YouTube video
too thank you for that um okay so anyway
that's what we're going to do today
we're g to try to uh we're going to try
to get this test done and then we're if
we have time we'll move on and we'll
start we'll finish the build script uh
we we'll we'll inject the harbor
namespace building into it even though
people just assume it's there I actually
want to add I like being able to run uh
just run the build script and have it
detect whether the Nam space Harbor
already exists and say oh I don't want
to blow away the existing namespace in
this thing I want to I want it I want
the build thing to actually not blow
away the existing one unless it's you
know explicitly done and and if it's not
there add it right so we got to add that
that's pretty easy to add to the build
script uh actually that is um that might
be uh well let me think about this this
for a
second I'm trying to decide whether we
want to put it in the we want the build
script to in the current format build is
not a well we'll talk about it later
whether it goes in there I I'm I'm
hesitating because build doesn't have
doesn't necessarily have visibility into
the into the cluster to find that out
um but possibly it's okay to do that I'm
actually going to ask my teammate on
that um okay so then we we'll get to the
deploy script these are all the things
that we have to do right so if you want
to stay tuned you or you're just watch
the Youtube video tomorrow and I can
report on what we did um if you want to
follow along in the repo the repo
is uh that's the Harbor Docks where is
the repo the re the repo
is
uh no it's uh RX robkes app slh
Harbor and it's the branch the branch is
um uh the pr that you want to follow
along with is modernizing the latest
Kates app this is a draft PR um it
should be a draft yeah and you can
actually see all the files that were
changed um that I did try to put kind of
a uh I don't know if you saw but I did
try to put a like those things that have
to be done here um as checkboxes but
that's I don't know I'm also just using
the not SP so if you want to keep up
with what's going on on that let me know
um especially if you've got kubernetes
knowledge and you think I'm doing
something bad um
uh how you doing stormy um I actually
am
not uh very good at kubernetes there I
said it I'm not because I don't like it
I'm more of a Senior Systems API
developer even though I have I'm also
bad at that end times I'm I'm not the
best okay I'm just not so if you're
looking at me looking for the best
possible thing you know no I I'm good at
stuff but this is a good place for you
to come figure this stuff out so it's
very likely that I've made huge mistakes
and stuff and if you you see anything
wrong let me know um and we'll go with
that all right so that's the end of this
video um and we'll see you bye